//Quizzes Data

export const quizData = {
    "physics": {
      1:[
        {
          question: "The change in the direction of a wave passing from one medium to another is termed as —————.",
          option1: "Interference",
          option2: "Mirage",
          option3: "Diffraction",
          option4: "Refraction",
          answer: "Refraction"
        },
        {
          question: "What would be the angle of incidence for a light ray having zero reflection angle?",
          option1: "180 degrees",
          option2: "90 degrees",
          option3: "0 degree",
          option4: "45 degrees",
          answer: "0 degree"
        },
        {
          question: "Light can be focused on our retina through which of the following phenomena?",
          option1: "Interference",
          option2: "Refraction",
          option3: "Diffraction",
          option4: "Mirage",
          answer: "Refraction"
        },
        {
          question: "Speed of light in a vacuum is represented as —————.",
          option1: "a",
          option2: "v",
          option3: "c",
          option4: "l",
          answer: "c"
        },
        {
          question: "A full length of the image of a distant tall building can be seen using —————.",
          option1: "a convex mirror",
          option2: "a plane mirror",
          option3: "a concave mirror",
          option4: "none of the options",
          answer:"a convex mirror"
        }
      ],
      2:[
        {
          question: "Which of the following is the good conductor of electricity?",
          option1: "Paper",
          option2: "Iron",
          option3: "Glass",
          option4: "Ebonite",
          answer: "Iron"
        },
        {
          question: "The SI unit of electric current is ———.",
          option1: "Volt",
          option2: "Faraday",
          option3: "Ampere",
          option4: "Ohms",
          answer: "Ampere"
        },
        {
          question: "Electrical resistivity of a metallic wire depends upon its ———.",
          option1: "Length",
          option2: "Material",
          option3: "Thickness",
          option4: "Shape",
          answer: "Material"
        },
        {
          question: "Electric current is measured using ————–.",
          option1: "Galvanometer",
          option2: "Ammeter",
          option3: "Voltmeter",
          option4: "Potentiometer",
          answer: "Ammeter"
        },
        {
          question: "Unit of electric power may also be expressed as ————–.",
          option1: "Watt second",
          option2: "Ampere hour",
          option3: "Volt second",
          option4: "Kilowatt hour",
          answer: "Kilowatt hour"
        }
      ],
      3:[
        {
          question: "Scattering of light can be seen in ————-.",
          option1: "blue colour of sky",
          option2: "reddening of the Sun at sunrise",
          option3: "reddening of the Sun at sunset",
          option4: "All of the above",
          answer: "All of the above"
        },
        {
          question: "The change in focal length of the human eye is caused due to ————-.",
          option1: "Cornea",
          option2: "Iris",
          option3: "Ciliary muscles",
          option4: "Pupil",
          answer: "Ciliary muscles"
        },
        {
          question: "The ability of the eye lens to adjust its focal length is called ————-.",
          option1: "Indexing of eye",
          option2: "Accommodation of eye",
          option3: "Vision restoration",
          option4: "Adaptivity of eye",
          answer: "Accommodation of eye"
        },
        {
          question: "How does the eye change in order to focus on near or distant objects?",
          option1: "The lens moves in or out",
          option2: "The pupil gets smaller",
          option3: "The retina moves in or out",
          option4: "The lens becomes thicker or thinner",
          answer: "The lens becomes thicker or thinner"
        },
        {
          question: "The crystalline lens of people at old age becomes milky and cloudy; this condition is known as ————-.",
          option1: "Hypermetropia",
          option2: "Myopia",
          option3: "Cataract",
          option4: "Presbyopia",
          answer: "Cataract"
        }
      ],
      4:[
        {
          question: "The ratio of the sine of the angle of incidence to the sine of the angle of refraction is constant. It is given by —————.",
          option1: "Faraday’s law",
          option2: "Snell’s law",
          option3: "Newton’s law",
          option4: "Murphy’s law",
          answer: "Snell’s law"
        },
        {
          question: "Twinkling of stars is due to which optical phenomenon?",
          option1: "Reflection",
          option2: "Interference",
          option3: "Refraction",
          option4: "Divergence",
          answer: "Refraction"
        },
        {
          question: "The laws of reflection are valid for —————.",
          option1: "a convex mirror",
          option2: "a plane mirror",
          option3: "a concave mirror",
          option4: "all mirrors irrespective of their shape",
          answer: "all mirrors irrespective of their shape"
        },
        {
          question: "Light from the Sun falling on a convex lens will converge at —————.",
          option1: "Radius of curvature",
          option2: "Optical centre",
          option3: "Focus",
          option4: "None of the options",
          answer: "Focus"
        },
        {
          question: "Concave lens produces —————.",
          option1: "only virtual image",
          option2: "only erect image",
          option3: "only diminished image",
          option4: "virtual, erect, and diminished image",
          answer: "virtual, erect, and diminished image"
        }
    ],
    5:[
        {
          question: "Materials which do not allow electricity to pass through are known as —————–.",
          option1: "Semiconductor",
          option2: "Conductor",
          option3: "Insulator",
          option4: "Semi-insulator",
          answer: "Insulator"
        },
        {
          question: "Tungsten is used in which of the following?",
          option1: "Metal extraction",
          option2: "Electric bulb",
          option3: "Insulators",
          option4: "Textile manufacturing",
          answer: "Electric bulb"
        },
        {
          question: "Electric potential is a ————.",
          option1: "Vector quantity",
          option2: "Scalar quantity",
          option3: "Dimensionless quantity",
          option4: "None of these option",
          answer: "Scalar quantity"
        },
        {
          question: "Copper is used in electric transmission lines because ———————-.",
          option1: "High resistivity",
          option2: "Low resistivity",
          option3: "No resistivity",
          option4: "None of these option",
          answer: "Low resistivity"
        },
        {
          question: "The SI unit of resistance is ————.",
          option1: "Volt",
          option2: "Faraday",
          option3: "Ampere",
          option4: "Ohm",
          answer: "Ohm"
        }
      ]                        
    },
    "maths": {
      1: [
        {
          question: "The decimal expansion of 22/7 is",
          option1: "Terminating",
          option2: "Non-terminating and repeating",
          option3: "Non-terminating and Non-repeating",
          option4: "None of the above",
          answer: "Non-terminating and repeating"
        },
        {
          question: "For some integer n, the odd integer is represented in the form of",
          option1: "n",
          option2: "n + 1",
          option3: "2n + 1",
          option4: "2n",
          answer: "2n + 1"
        },
        {
          question: "HCF of 26 and 91 is:",
          option1: "15",
          option2: "13",
          option3: "19",
          option4: "11",
          answer: "13"
        },
        {
          question: "Which of the following is not irrational?",
          option1: "3 + √7",
          option2: "3 - √7",
          option3: "(3 + √7)(3 - √7)",
          option4: "3√7",
          answer: "(3 + √7)(3 - √7)"
        },
        {
          question: "The addition of a rational number and an irrational number is equal to:",
          option1: "rational number",
          option2: "Irrational number",
          option3: "Both",
          option4: "None of the above",
          answer: "Irrational number"
        }
      ],
      2: [
        {
          question: "The zeroes of x^2 - 2x - 8 are:",
          option1: "2, -4",
          option2: "4, -2",
          option3: "-2, -2",
          option4: "-4, -4",
          answer: "4, -2"
        },
        {
          question: "What is the quadratic polynomial whose sum and the product of zeroes is √2, ⅓ respectively?",
          option1: "3x^2 - 3√2x + 1",
          option2: "3x^2 + 3√2x + 1",
          option3: "3x^2 + 3√2x - 1",
          option4: "None of the above",
          answer: "3x^2 - 3√2x + 1"
        },
        {
          question: "If the zeroes of the quadratic polynomial ax^2 + bx + c, c≠0 are equal, then",
          option1: "c and b have opposite signs",
          option2: "c and a have opposite signs",
          option3: "c and b have same signs",
          option4: "c and a have same signs",
          answer: "c and a have same signs"
        },
        {
          question: "The degree of the polynomial, x^4 - x^2 + 2 is",
          option1: "2",
          option2: "4",
          option3: "1",
          option4: "0",
          answer: "4"
        },
        {
          question: "If one of the zeroes of cubic polynomial is x^3 + ax^2 + bx + c is -1, then product of other two zeroes is:",
          option1: "b - a - 1",
          option2: "b - a + 1",
          option3: "a - b + 1",
          option4: "a - b - 1",
          answer: "b - a + 1"
        }
      ],
      3:[
        {
          question: "Which of the following triangles have the same side lengths?",
          option1: "Scalene",
          option2: "Isosceles",
          option3: "Equilateral",
          option4: "None of these",
          answer: "Equilateral"
        },
        {
          question: "Area of an equilateral triangle with side length a is equal to:",
          option1: "(√3/2)a",
          option2: "(√3/2)a^2",
          option3: "(√3/4)a^2",
          option4: "(√3/4)a",
          answer: "(√3/4)a^2"
        },
        {
          question: "D and E are the midpoints of side AB and AC of a triangle ABC, respectively and BC = 6 cm. If DE || BC, then the length (in cm) of DE is:",
          option1: "2.5",
          option2: "3",
          option3: "5",
          option4: "6",
          answer: "3"
        },
        {
          question: "The diagonals of a rhombus are 16 cm and 12 cm in length. The side of the rhombus in length is:",
          option1: "20 cm",
          option2: "8 cm",
          option3: "10 cm",
          option4: "9 cm",
          answer: "10 cm"
        },
        {
          question: "Corresponding sides of two similar triangles are in the ratio of 2:3. If the area of the small triangle is 48 sq.cm, then the area of large triangle is:",
          option1: "230 sq.cm",
          option2: "106 sq.cm",
          option3: "107 sq.cm",
          option4: "108 sq.cm",
          answer: "108 sq.cm"
        }
      ],
      4: [
        {
          question: "In ∆ ABC, right-angled at B, AB = 24 cm, BC = 7 cm. The value of tan C is:",
          option1: "12/7",
          option2: "24/7",
          option3: "20/7",
          option4: "7/24",
          answer: "24/7"
        },
        {
          question: "(Sin 30°+cos 60°)-(sin 60° + cos 30°) is equal to:",
          option1: "0",
          option2: "1+2√3",
          option3: "1-√3",
          option4: "1+√3",
          answer: "1-√3"
        },
        {
          question: "The value of tan 60°/cot 30° is equal to:",
          option1: "0",
          option2: "1",
          option3: "2",
          option4: "3",
          answer: "1"
        },
        {
          question: "1 – cos2A is equal to:",
          option1: "sin2A",
          option2: "tan2A",
          option3: "1 – sin2A",
          option4: "sec2A",
          answer: "sin2A"
        },
        {
          question: "sin (90° – A) and cos A are:",
          option1: "Different",
          option2: "Same",
          option3: "Not related",
          option4: "None of the above",
          answer: "Same"
        }
      ],
      5:[
        {
          question: "A circle has a number of tangents equal to",
          option1: "0",
          option2: "1",
          option3: "2",
          option4: "Infinite",
          answer: "Infinite"
        },
        {
          question: "A tangent intersects the circle at:",
          option1: "One point",
          option2: "Two distinct points",
          option3: "At the circle",
          option4: "None of the above",
          answer: "One point"
        },
        {
          question: "A circle can have _____parallel tangents at a single time.",
          option1: "One",
          option2: "Two",
          option3: "Three",
          option4: "Four",
          answer: "Two"
        },
        {
          question: "If the angle between two radii of a circle is 110º, then the angle between the tangents at the ends of the radii is:",
          option1: "90º",
          option2: "50º",
          option3: "70º",
          option4: "40º",
          answer: "70º"
        },
        {
          question: "The length of the tangent from an external point A on a circle with centre O is",
          option1: "always greater than OA",
          option2: "equal to OA",
          option3: "always less than OA",
          option4: "cannot be estimated",
          answer: "always less than OA"
        }
      ]
    },
    "chemistry":{
        1:[
            {
              question: "What is the rate of chemical reaction?",
              option1: "Chemical reaction rate is a chemical property",
              option2: "Chemical reaction rate is a physical property",
              option3: "Chemical reaction rate is an intensive property",
              option4: "Chemical reaction rate is an extensive property",
              answer: "Chemical reaction rate is an intensive property"
            },
            {
              question: "The term “catalyst” refers to ___________",
              option1: "Can either increase or decrease the speed of a chemical reaction",
              option2: "Alters the value of equilibrium constant in a reversible chemical reaction",
              option3: "Increases the speed of a chemical reaction",
              option4: "Decreases the speed of a chemical reaction",
              answer: "Can either increase or decrease the speed of a chemical reaction"
            },
            {
              question: "The reaction order is determined by",
              option1: "Power of any one of the reactant concentrations",
              option2: "Number of molecules of reactants taking part in the reaction",
              option3: "Sum of the powers of the concentrations of all the reactants",
              option4: "Concentration of intermediate species formed",
              answer: "Sum of the powers of the concentrations of all the reactants"
            },
            {
              question: "The rate of homogeneous response is influenced by a number of factors.",
              option1: "Temperature only",
              option2: "Pressure only",
              option3: "Reactant Concentration only",
              option4: "Temperature, pressure and reactant concentration",
              answer: "Temperature, pressure and reactant concentration"
            },
            {
              question: "A reaction’s rate cannot be expressed in terms of time.",
              option1: "Volume of reacting fluid",
              option2: "Volume of solid",
              option3: "Amount of product",
              option4: "Interfacial surface",
              answer: "Amount of product"
            }
          ],
          2:[
            {
              question: "The number of molecules engaged in an elementary reaction is referred to as ____",
              option1: "Molecularity",
              option2: "Order of reaction",
              option3: "Unimolecular reaction",
              option4: "Rate of reaction",
              answer: "Molecularity"
            },
            {
              question: "Only liquid pressure is measured with which of the following instruments?",
              option1: "Differential Manometer",
              option2: "Manometer",
              option3: "Piezometer",
              option4: "None of the mentioned",
              answer: "Piezometer"
            },
            {
              question: "Which of the following statements concerning basic reactions is correct?",
              option1: "They occur in multiple steps",
              option2: "They are complex in nature",
              option3: "Order of elementary reaction is an integer",
              option4: "All first order reactions are elementary",
              answer: "Order of elementary reaction is an integer"
            },
            {
              question: "A state function is which of the following?",
              option1: "Entropy",
              option2: "Heat",
              option3: "Work",
              option4: "None of the mentioned",
              answer: "Entropy"
            },
            {
              question: "What is the conservation of Bernoulli’s Equation?",
              option1: "Pressure",
              option2: "Energy",
              option3: "Mass",
              option4: "Momentum",
              answer: "Energy"
            }
          ],
          3:[
            {
              question: "Which Acid is present in Tomato?",
              option1: "Citric Acid",
              option2: "Oxalic Acid",
              option3: "Lactic Acid",
              option4: "HCl",
              answer: "Oxalic Acid"
            },
            {
              question: "Which of the following is a strong acid?",
              option1: "HCl pH 1",
              option2: "CH3COOH pH 5",
              option3: "Lemon juice pH 2.2",
              option4: "Pure Milk pH 6",
              answer: "HCl pH 1"
            },
            {
              question: "Na2CO3.10H2O is known as –",
              option1: "Baking soda",
              option2: "Baking powder",
              option3: "Washing soda",
              option4: "Bleaching powder",
              answer: "Washing soda"
            },
            {
              question: "pH value less than 7 indicates that the solution is –",
              option1: "Acidic",
              option2: "Basic",
              option3: "Neutral",
              option4: "No effect",
              answer: "Acidic"
            },
            {
              question: "Which of the following is neutral salt?",
              option1: "NH4Cl",
              option2: "CH3COONH4",
              option3: "CH3COONa",
              option4: "Na2CO3",
              answer: "CH3COONH4"
            }
          ],
          4:[
            {
              question: "When hydrochloric acid is added to barium hydroxide, a white-coloured compound is formed. Which of the following option gives the complete chemical reaction?",
              option1: "HCl + Ba(OH)2 → BaCl2 + 2HOH",
              option2: "2HCl + Ba(OH)2 → BaCl2 + 2HOH",
              option3: "2HCl + Ba(OH)2 → BaH2 + 2HCl + O2",
              option4: "HCl + 2Ba(OH) → 2BaCl2 + 2HOH + O2",
              answer: "2HCl + Ba(OH)2 → BaCl2 + 2HOH"
            },
            {
              question: "What happens when a pellet of sodium is dropped in water?",
              option1: "It catches fire and forms oxide",
              option2: "It absorbs heat and forms oxide",
              option3: "It catches fire and forms hydroxide",
              option4: "It absorbs heat and forms hydroxide",
              answer: "It catches fire and forms hydroxide"
            },
            {
              question: "The chemical reaction between a piece of copper and nitric acid is given by the chemical equations, Cu + HNO3 → Cu(NO3)2 + H2. H2 + HNO3 → H2O + NO2. What can be inferred from the chemical equation?",
              option1: "Copper causes the oxidation of HNO3 to form NO2",
              option2: "Hydrogen gas gets oxidised by HNO3 to form water",
              option3: "Gas reacts with oxygen in the air to form water",
              option4: "Nitrate reacts with hydrogen to form NO2 and H2O",
              answer: "Hydrogen gas gets oxidised by HNO3 to form water"
            },
            {
              question: "Which of the following options gives the process of extraction of mercury from its ore cinnabar?",
              option1: "Cooling cinnabar in the presence of excess air",
              option2: "Cooling cinnabar to convert it into mercuric oxide and then heating it",
              option3: "Cinnabar to convert it into mercuric oxide and then heating it again",
              option4: "Cinnabar in the presence of limited air, and then adding a small amount of water",
              answer: "Cinnabar to convert it into mercuric oxide and then heating it again"
            },
            {
                question: "The metals that float when treated with water are:",
                option1: "Manganese and sodium",
                option2: "Sodium and calcium",
                option3: "Magnesium and sodium",
                option4: "Magnesium and calcium",
                answer: "Magnesium and calcium"
              }
          ],
          5:[
            {
                question: "Which of the following forms the basis of the modern periodic table?",
                option1: "Atomic mass",
                option2: "Atomic number",
                option3: "Number of nucleons",
                option4: "All of the above",
                answer: "Atomic number"
              },
              {
                question: "Which of the following is the most reactive element of group 17?",
                option1: "Oxygen",
                option2: "Sodium",
                option3: "Fluorine",
                option4: "Magnesium",
                answer: "Fluorine"
              },
              {
                question: "Which of the following is the correct order of the atomic radii of the elements oxygen, fluorine and nitrogen?",
                option1: "O < F < N",
                option2: "N < F < O",
                option3: "O < N < F",
                option4: "F < O < N",
                answer: "F < O < N"
              },
              {
                question: "Element X forms a chloride with the formula XCl2, which is solid with a high melting point. X would most likely be in the same group of the Periodic Table as:",
                option1: "Na",
                option2: "Mg",
                option3: "Al",
                option4: "Si",
                answer: "Mg"
              },
              {
                question: "What happens to the electropositive character of elements on moving from left to right in a periodic table?",
                option1: "Increase",
                option2: "Decreases",
                option3: "First increases, then decreases",
                option4: "First decreases, then increases",
                answer: "Decreases"
              }              
          ]
          
                              
    }
  };
  